Md Moktarul Alam

Contact: 203/Apon Neloy, House:39-41, Road:04, Block: C, Monsurabad Residential Area, Adabor Sub town, Shymoli, Mohammadpur, Dhaka-1207. Bangladesh Cell: +8801743280728 (Call/Whatsapp)

Email: moktaruleee@gmail.com

Career Summary

I used to lead them in activities like disciplines, punctuality, cultural aspects, sports activities, academic motivations, and, most importantly, maintaining good relationships. These huge responsibilities from the prefect ship position had helped me a lot to improve my self-confidence and leadership qualities. Besides my Profession, one of my biggest passions is working as a researcher show anchor on different online platforms and directly to join the meeting. I am currently writing some papers on my work to publish a good journal for future technology. In my research papers which are already published, people read them, and some papers have citation also. I think that my research work will be helpful for future generation. My long-term career goal is to become a competent and successful RF and Antenna Specialist in my country and worldwide. And I will establish my own research work, where I would like to start work in a Satellite center, Antenna related.

Professional Experiences

Presently work as a researcher in BUET and home tutor.

Process Engineer- Edison Group, Zirabo, Ashulia, Dhaka (October, 2019-April 2020)

- Design the whole process to assembly the mobile phone.
- Find out the problem in the assembly time and try to solve the problem.
- To maintain the product quality with reasonable price.
- Support the start-up and analysis the work whole process time.

Executive Operations- OK WORLD Banani, Dhaka-1213 (June 2019- September 2019)

- Develop corrective actions to solve the operations issues.
- Ensure operations related activities are performed in compliance with company standards and regulations.
- Provide technical support and guidance on operations validation, development, and implementation.
- Support the start-up and integration of new operations projects.

Research Assistant- International Islamic University Malaysia (March 2017 -Feb 2019)

Time Diversity Technique to Mitigate Earth to Satellite Rain Fade in Malaysia

- To investigate available time diversity prediction models in earth-to-satellite rain fade mitigation.
- To analyze time diversity method using rain rate distributions for earth-to-satellite rain attenuation mitigation
- To develop a prediction model for time diversity gain based on measured rain rate distributions.
- To validate proposed time diversity gain model using measured rain rate and rain attenuation statistics

Teaching Assistant International Islamic University Malaysia (August 2017- April 2018)

Demonstrator on EECE 1313 Programing Language and Grader on Satellite Communication and Antenna

Education

- Master of Science (Electronics Engineering) from International Islamic University Malaysia Jalan Gombak, Selangor, KualaLumpur-53100, Malaysia during the period February 2017-February 2019 by Research (Extremely Good) Approximate CGPA 3.67 out of 4.00
- Bachelor of Science (Electrical and Electronics Engineering) from International Business Administration and Information System University (IBAIS), Dhaka during the period January 2012- April 2016. CGPA 3.34 out of 4.00
- Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) from BCIC College, Dhaka, Bangladesh. GPA 3.80 out of 5.00
- Secondary School Certificate (SSC) from Dinajpur Zilla School, Dinajpur, Bangladesh.
 GPA 4.81 out of 5.00

Language

- Bengali Mother tongue
- English- Education and Job

Skills

- Process strong interpersonal, communication, analytical and time management Microsoft office (Word, Excel, Power point,)
- Lab View PSpice, OrCAD capture 9.2, Proteus, DSCH 2, MATLAB, Microsoft Visual Studio C/C++, Xilinx design Suite.
- Try to learn from the learner master about new technologies and skills

Publication

- Rafiqul, Islam Md, Md Moktarul Alam, Ali Kodhim Lwas, and Sarah Yasmin Mohamad. "Rain Rate Distributions for Microwave Link Design Based on Long Term Measurement in Malaysia." Indonesian Journal of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science 10, no. 3 (2018): 1023-1029.
- Rafiqul, I. M., Lwas, A. K., Habaebi, M. H., Alam, M. M., Chebil, J., Mandeep, J. S., & Zyoud, A. (2018). Analysis of Time Diversity Gain for Satellite Communication Link Based on Ku-Band Rain Attenuation Data Measured in Malaysia. International Journal of Electrical and Computer Engineering (IJECE), 8(4).
- Md Moktarul Alam, Islam Md. Rafiqul, Khairayu Badron and Farah Dyana A. R. "Time Diversity Gain Analysis for Earth to Satellite Link Based on Measured Rain Rate." 2018 7th International Conference on Computer and Communication Engineering (ICCCE). 2018.
- Md Moktarul Alam, Md Rafiqul Islam, M. A. Salam, Norhafizah Muhammad "Prediction of Rain Rate Distribution with Time Delay Based on Measured 1-minute Rain Intensity Data to Mitigate Fades on Satellite Link." 7th Brunei International Conference on Engineering and Technology 2018 Paper Id: 190, 2018.
- Md Moktarul Alam, Islam Md Rafiqul, Khairayu Badron, Farah Diyana, Lwas, Ali Kadhim "Proposed Time Diversity Analysis Based on Rain Rate Data to Mitigate Rain Fade Over EarthSatellite link." International Journal of Satellite Communications and Networking. SAT-18-0034, 2018.
- Alam, Md Moktarul, Islam Md Rafiqul, Khairayu Badron, Hassaan Dao, M. Rofiqul Hassan, and Ali Kadhim Lwas. "Investigation of Time Diversity Gain for Earth to Satellite Link Using Rain Rate Gain." Bulletin of Electrical Engineering and Informatics 8, no. 3 (2019).
- Md Moktarul Alam, Islam Md Rafiqul, Khairayu Badron, Momin Mullah, "Modelling of Rain Rate Gain to Mitigate Rain Fades for Satellite Links Design." Technology Reports of Kansai University Acknowledgement 18111303, ISSN: 04532198 Volume 62, Issue 07, August 2020.
- ➤ Olanrewaju, R. F., Khan, B. U. I., Khan, A. R., Yaacob, M., & Alam, M. M. (2018). Efficient cache replacement policy for minimizing error rate in L2-STT-MRAM caches. International Journal of Grid and Utility Computing, 9(4), 307-321.

Activities

- Cognitive Approach to Building a Safe and Smart City Fawzi Behmann President TelNet Management Consulting Inc. Vice-Chair, IEEE NA Communications Society
- TECHNICAL TALK MASSIVE-MIMO IN THE FUTURE WIRELESS CELLULAR NETWORK SPEAKER Prof. Vahid Meghdadi
- ISA TRANSACTION in recognition of the review contributed to the journal

References

Dr. Md. Rafiqul Islam Professor of Propagation and Antenna Electrical and Computer Engineering International Islamic University, Malaysia

Mobile: +60192580804 Email: rafiq@iium.edu.my Dr. Liakot Ali Professor

Institute of Information and Communication

Technology

Bangladesh University of Engineering and

Technology (BUET) Mobile: +8801766924290 Email: liakot@iict.buet.ac.bd

I, hereby, am stating that all information mentioned above is absolutely correct with the best of knowledge.

Date: 21/05/2021 Signature: Moktanul Alama

Md Moktarul Alam